Inventory of the Williamsburg Area League of Women Voters Papers, 1977-1993
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Williamsburg Area League of Women Voters Papers 1977-1993
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
2006.53
536 items in 17 folders (2 boxes)
Operational and historical files of the Williamsburg chapter of the League of Women Voters
Peggy Kossler
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 2006.
Historical Information
The Williamsburg Area League of Women Voters has also been known in the past as the League of Women Voters of Williamsburg, Va., and the League of Women Voters of Williamsburg-James City County. These names appear to have been used at times interchangeably.
Scope and Content
Files of the Williamsburg Area League of Women Voters (WALWV). Includes letters written by WALWV leadership to members of the Virginia U.S congressional delegation, newspaper clippings (1980-1991) pertaining to issues of concern for WALWV (such as technology, lab and genetic science, redistricting, city and county infrastructure), additional clippings regarding local elections and legislative concerns, handwritten notes on issues of concern, WALWV newsletters (1983-1984, partial), copies of LWV national publication Voter (Winter 1984, Spring 1981, Spring 1984, Fall 1984 and Winter 1984 issues), LWV-produced Virginia legislative guides (1985), materials pertaining to Virginia state LWV conventions (1989, 1993), typed draft manuscript for study of Peninsula governments (Williamsburg and the counties of James City and York), printed speeches, documents regarding local league activities.
Arrangement
This collection is maintained as organized by Peggy Kossler, grouped by material subject.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Williamsburg Area League of Women Voters
Geographical Names:
Williamsburg (Va.)
Persons:
Kossler, Peggy
Contents List
- Newspaper Clippings 1983-1985 (Folder I-1)
  Newspaper clippings regarding issues of possible concern to league (e.g., technology, environment, science) primarily from tidewater newspapers (64 items)
- WALWV Newsletters and Source Materials 1983-1984 (Folder 2)
  WALWV newsletter materials (1983-1984), including drafts of newsletters, source materials for articles (information on the federal budget), partial series of newsletters (40 items)
- Newspaper Clippings 1980-1984 (Folder 3)
  Clippings (1980-1984) regarding local government elections and candidates (31 items)
- State and National LWV Publications 1979-1985 (Folder 4)
  State and national LWV publications, including five editions of Voter magazine (Winter 1979, Spring 1981, Spring 1984, Fall 1984, Winter 1984) and two (unique) 1985 guides to the Virginia state legislature (7 items)
- LWV State Convention Information, 1989 and 1993 1989, 1993 (Folder 5)
  State LWV convention materials for 1989 and 1993, in Charlottesville and Williamsburg, respectively. Preliminary plans, press releases, hotel plans. (43 items)
- Newspaper Clippings and Correspondence 1980-1989 (Folder 6)
  Newspaper clippings and handwritten notes pertaining to annexation and redistricting (1980-1989), letter from Peggy Kossler to state LWV committee chair concerning voting patterns in Williamsburg and counties of James City and York (1981). (22 items)
- LWV Urban Concerns Materials 1977-1979 (Folder 7)
  Urban concerns of the WALWV: printed materials and handwritten notes of Peggy Klossen, c. 1977-1979. (19 items)
- Newspaper Clippings 1980-1992 (Folder 8)
  Clippings from 1980-1992 regarding budgets, stoplights, roads, industrial bonds and other city concerns, letter from George Grayson regarding finance. (100 items)
- Williamsburg League Activity Materials 1990-1993 (Folder 9)
  WALWV activities in the early 1990s: newsletters and posters, 1990-91 Virginia Legislative Directory. (29 items)
- Newspaper Clippings and Correspondence 1983-1993 (Folder 10)
  Clippings (1983-1993) regarding federal tax reform, letter by Peggy Kossler to congressmen regarding federal debt reduction (various forms of same message, sent to multiple Virginia delegates). (69 items)
- State and National League Materials 1977-1993 (Folder 11)
  Printed materials regarding the statewide and national LWV organization, including pamphlets covering Virginia state government, LWV positions on state and national issues, examples of pamphlets produced by other local and regional chapters; printed materials date from 1977 to 1992. (13 items)
- Chapter Operation Materials 1980s-1992 (Folder 12)
  Printed materials (1980s-1992) from national and state LWV organization regarding chapter operation and governmental and constitutional issues. Materials include the Leader's Guides, "Update on Planning Districts" in Virginia (April 1979), information on 1988 presidential debates, and pamphlets on reproductive rights. (16 items)
- Peninsula Government Manuscript late 1970s (Folder 13)
  Typed draft manuscript (grouped in sections) for study of Peninsula governments (Williamsburg, counties of James City and York). Detailed examination of operations, includes regional citizens advisory boards (late 1970s). (15 items)
- National LWV Printed Materials 1983-1988 (Folder 14)
  Printed materials from national office, including "Memorandum," "Action Alert," "Report from the Hill" (1983-1988). (29 items)
- Printed Speeches 1985, 1987 (Folder 15)
  Printed speeches of (1) Dorothy Ridings, National LWV President (1985), and (2) Clement Bezold, Director of the Institute for Alternative Futures, "Future Horizons for Virginia" (1987). (2 items)
- WALWV Activity, State and Local Bylaws 1977-1985 (Folder 16)
  Documents regarding local league activities, bylaws of state and local organization (1977-1985), proposed 1984/85 WALWV budget. (10 items)
- Miscellaneous 1977-1993 (Folder 17)
  Miscellaneous printed materials, regarding issues relevant to national and local league activities. (47 items)